[
  {
    "id": "T4B01",
    "correct": 1,
    "question": "What is the effect of excessive microphone gain on SSB transmissions?",
    "answers": [
      "Frequency instability",
      "Distorted transmitted audio",
      "Increased SWR",
      "All these choices are correct"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B02",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "Which of the following can be used to enter a transceiver’s operating frequency?",
    "answers": [
      "The keypad or VFO knob",
      "The CTCSS or DTMF encoder",
      "The Automatic Frequency Control",
      "All these choices are correct"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B03",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "How is squelch adjusted so that a weak FM signal can be heard?",
    "answers": [
      "Set the squelch threshold so that receiver output audio is on all the time",
      "Turn up the audio level until it overcomes the squelch threshold",
      "Turn on the anti-squelch function",
      "Enable squelch enhancement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B04",
    "correct": 1,
    "question": "What is a way to enable quick access to a favorite frequency or channel on your transceiver?",
    "answers": [
      "Enable the frequency offset",
      "Store it in a memory channel",
      "Enable the VOX",
      "Use the scan mode to select the desired frequency"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B05",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "What does the scanning function of an FM transceiver do?",
    "answers": [
      "Checks incoming signal deviation",
      "Prevents interference to nearby repeaters",
      "Tunes through a range of frequencies to check for activity",
      "Checks for messages left on a digital bulletin board"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B06",
    "correct": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following controls could be used if the voice pitch of a single-sideband signal returning to your CQ call seems too high or low?",
    "answers": [
      "The AGC or limiter",
      "The bandwidth selection",
      "The tone squelch",
      "The RIT or Clarifier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B07",
    "correct": 1,
    "question": "What does a DMR “code plug” contain?",
    "answers": [
      "Your call sign in CW for automatic identification",
      "Access information for repeaters and talkgroups",
      "The codec for digitizing audio",
      "The DMR software version"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B08",
    "correct": 1,
    "question": "What is the advantage of having multiple receive bandwidth choices on a multimode transceiver?",
    "answers": [
      "Permits monitoring several modes at once by selecting a separate filter for each mode",
      "Permits noise or interference reduction by selecting a bandwidth matching the mode",
      "Increases the number of frequencies that can be stored in memory",
      "Increases the amount of offset between receive and transmit frequencies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B09",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "How is a specific group of stations selected on a digital voice transceiver?",
    "answers": [
      "By retrieving the frequencies from transceiver memory",
      "By enabling the group’s CTCSS tone",
      "By entering the group’s identification code",
      "By activating automatic identification"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B10",
    "correct": 2,
    "question": "Which of the following receiver filter bandwidths provides the best signal-to-noise ratio for SSB reception?",
    "answers": [
      "500 Hz",
      "1000 Hz",
      "2400 Hz",
      "5000 Hz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B11",
    "correct": 0,
    "question": "Which of the following must be programmed into a D-STAR digital transceiver before transmitting?",
    "answers": [
      "Your call sign",
      "Your output power",
      "The codec type being used",
      "All these choices are correct"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "T4B12",
    "correct": 3,
    "question": "What is the result of tuning an FM receiver above or below a signal’s frequency?",
    "answers": [
      "Change in audio pitch",
      "Sideband inversion",
      "Generation of a heterodyne tone",
      "Distortion of the signal’s audio"
    ]
  }
]